academyart.edu 2019-12-14

# Privacy Policy & Terms of Use | Academy of Art University

Academy of Art University seeks to protect your personal and private information. Any such information you submit on this website is for official Academy of Art University use only. Please carefully review the Privacy Policy of Academy of Art University’s website (below) to learn about how the University collects, uses and protects any information you provide on or through the website, and your choices for managing your Personal Information. By using the Site, you agree to this Policy. This Policy is subject to the Terms of Service posted on the website.

**Managing Personal Information**

You may review, correct, update or change your Personal Information, or remove your Personal Information from direct marketing efforts, at any time by contacting Academy of Art University at:

Academy of Art University  
79 New Montgomery Street  
San Francisco, CA 94105-3410  
1-800-544-2787 (US only)  
1-415-274-2200  
info@academyart.edu

**Information Collection & Use **

Any information you submit on this website is for official Academy of Art University use only. Information will not be sold or rented to any company or organization. As such, the information that you submit will only be used for University purposes by the University itself or those designated as its agents. The following types of information may be collected:

**Personal Information**

Should you choose to provide it, Academy of Art University may collect information that personally identifies you, such as your name, address, telephone number, email address, billing information or other data which can be reasonably linked to such information (“Personal Information”). The decision to provide this information is optional; however, if you elect not to provide such information, you may not be able to access certain content or features on the Site.

**Non-Personal Information**

Academy of Art University automatically collects information that does not reflect or reference an individually identifiable user and does so to help understand how visitors use the website. Like most websites, the University website automatically collects and uses the data contained in log files, which may include your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP (internet service provider), the Web browser you used to visit the website (such as Internet Explorer or Firefox), the time you visited the website and which pages you visited on the website.

**Cookies**

Academy of Art University utilizes cookies (a small file containing a string of characters that uniquely identifies your Web browser). Most Web browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but you may reset your Web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, certain features of the website may not work if you delete or disable cookies. Certain Service Providers of Academy of Art University may use cookies in connection with the services they perform on the University’s behalf. Academy of Art University or its authorized service providers may use “remarketing” techniques to target messaging to you on third party web sites, which means that, by using cookies (as detailed above), your browser will anonymously (without including any personally identifiable information) inform the third party sites that you are a student at Academy of Art University so that you will receive authorized messaging from us or our authorized service providers on those third party sites and across the internet. You may opt-out of being tracked for such purposes by either enabling the “do not track” feature of your web browser.

**How Personal and Non-Personal Information is Used**

Non-Personal Information and Personal Information are used for University purposes only, including, but not limited to, processing applications, contacting visitors who indicate they would like to receive additional information from Academy of Art University and processing all other forms submitted through the site, etc. Academy of Art University will not sell, share, or rent Personal Information to third parties for their use, nor will the University otherwise disclose Personal Information to such third parties, without your express permission or as expressly disclosed in this Privacy Policy. From time to time, the University might establish a business relationship with other persons or entities whom the University believes to be trustworthy (“Service Providers”). These Service Providers receive the information reasonably necessary for them to perform services for Academy of Art University. Unless otherwise required by law, Academy of Art University does not disclose any Personal Information to third-parties; however, the University reserves the right to make exceptions, such as when it is believed that an emergency, illegal activity or some other reasonable basis exists for notifying or providing such information to the appropriate authorities.

**Security**

Information collected is stored on servers Academy of Art University manages, using standard security procedures and practices to protect information from unauthorized access, destruction, use, modification or disclosure. However, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while the University strives to protect information transmitted on or through its website, the University cannot and does not guarantee or warrant the security of any information you transmit on or through the website, and you do so at your own risk.

**Children’s Privacy Statement**

Academy of Art University does not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under the age of 13. If the University becomes aware that a child under the age of 13 has submitted Personal Information, the University will delete such information from its records.

**Privacy Policy Changes**

Academy of Art University may, at its sole and absolute discretion, change this Privacy Policy from time to time. Academy of Art University will post the Privacy Policy as changed on the website. Your continued use of the website constitutes your agreement to the Privacy Policy as changed. If you object to any such changes, your sole recourse shall be to cease using the University’s website.

**Deceased Student Record Handling & Awarding of Posthumous Degrees**

**Release of Deceased Student Records**

Education records are no longer protected under FERPA after a student’s death; consequently, the stewardship of records pertaining to a deceased individual is not a FERPA issue but a matter of institutional policy. During the first year after the death of the individual is recorded, Academy of Art University will release the educational records to family members and agencies contributing to the tuition payments of the student. Following the initial year, records will be provided to any individual upon request.

**Awarding of Posthumous Degrees**

The family or other interested parties of the deceased student may initiate a request for a posthumous degree through the Office of the Registrar’s Completion Committee. The committee will review the request and may recommend to the President the award of a posthumous degree, delivered to the family of the deceased. Posthumous degrees may be awarded when the student had satisfactorily completed at least two-thirds (2/3) of all coursework towards a degree and was actively enrolled at the time of death. Under special circumstances, the President or designee may grant the awarding of a posthumous degree or certificate for a student who has completed less than two-thirds (2/3) of the degree coursework. Petitions for a posthumous degree may be initiated at any time – there is no limit to how much time has transpired between the student’s passing and the request.

Effective Date: 3/7/2011
